Finding Aid for Bernard A. Galler Papers 1956-1996
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Video Material
  The Video Materials series consists of original 16mm films and videotapes and DVD copies of presentations by Galler on computer languages and demonstrations of the use of the IMB card punch and the Michigan Terminal Operating System (MTS).and a film on the U-M Computing Center's Concomp Project. All were produced by the University of Michigan Television Center. Also included in the collection is recording of part of a symposium held at Iowa State University honoring John V. Atanosoff. The main speaker discusses the patent lawsuit against Sperry-Rand that established Atanosoff's priority in the development of the electronic digital computer. (Original films are stored in Cold Room
  - Time-Sharing Capabilities: Parts 1 and 2, by Prof. Bernard Galler July 13, 1972, 2 EIAJ videotapes, converted to 1 DVD; 0066-1 (Box 29)
  - Use of the IBM 29 Punch Card: Parts ! and !!, 2 16mm films converted to 1 DVD (Box 29)
    - Part: Basic Operation of Card Punch (, 22: Minutes; 006-2-1
    - Part II: Advanced Use of Punch Cards, 29 minutes 40 seconds; 006-2-1
  - MTS [Intro to use of the Michigan Terminal System], betaSP videotape converted to 1 DVD; 006-3 (Box 29)
  - Introduction to Assembler Language: Parts 1 and 2 September 20, 1975, 2 3/d-inc videotapes converted to 1 DVD; 006-4 (Box 29)
  - John V. Atansoff Day Panel Discussion, at Iowa State Anniversary October 21, 1983, 1 3/4-inch tapes converted to DVD, 3 copies; 006-5 (Box 29)
  - "*MOMs film October 21, 1983, 1 3/4-inch tapes converted to DVD, 3 copies; 006-6 (Box 29)
    (work print footage and edited use print, notes in cannister)
  - ConComp Project circa 1966, 16mm film; 006-7